Patience Mafarachisi

Mobile: 07479549614 E-mail: Patiencemafarachisi@gmail.com

Location: Preston

Personal Profile:

Provisionally registered pharmacist after completion of pre-registration training during 2018-2019. Master of Pharmacy graduate from Keele university. A motivated and committed individual with a proven ability to effectively evaluate, organise, and prioritise work. I have practical experience working with patients in hospital and community settings with a particular focus on building relationships with my colleagues and every patient I come across and always offering patient-centered care when required. My experience is not only tied to working in the Pharmacy or health sector, but I have a successful history of securing funds from a university to raise money for a building project in the villages of Peru and emulated that success in my role as a business development officer. I completed a year internship with the City of Stoke on Trent, creating and advertising campaigns in order to raise awareness on the importance of education within one of England's poorest cities. Working in retail and hospitality has equipped me with excellent communication skills. I always meet strict deadlines and targets set to achieve company goals whilst remaining flexible and independent. Kindness, humility, positivity and loyalty go a long way and possessing all these characteristics has proven useful when building relationships both professionally and socially.

Employment History

Pharmacist Manager -(2020-Present) Sharoe Green Pharmacy Key Responsibilities

- Act as responsible pharmacist
- Manage pharmacy staff lead staff members in the pharmacy by assigning work tasks, supervising, evaluating, hiring, firing, training, and scheduling work shifts for all employees.
- Perform clinical and accuracy checks on all prescriptions and MDS trays
- Consult with patients -advise patients and give them proper directions for taking prescription drugs, supplements, and over-the-counter medications.
- Communicate effectively with customers relating to queries and issues
- Administering flu jabs during flu season and help administer covid-19 vaccines and covid-19 booster jabs to patients, following all safety and cleanliness procedures.
- In charge of stock inventory and staying within budget
- Ensure the correct storage and handling of control drugs in addition to making entries in the control drug register
- Positively engage hospital pharmacists and doctor surgeries to ensure a high level of care for vulnerable patients.

Business Development Officer - (September 2019-July 2020 **) Goldsmith Personnel Ltd.**

Key Responsibilities

- Supporting the Director with tender management and bid writing: from initial scoping, through to the production of pre-qualification questionnaires and tender submissions.
- Formulating policies whilst supporting managers to create standard operating procedures

- within departments.
- Representing the company by engaging with internal and external stakeholders (NHS & Local Council) and maintaining professional and timely communications with all concerned in the bidding, commercial projects space and service user discharges.
- Procurement of clinical PPE and equipment to ensure that all company branches are adequately stocked.

Achievements

Positively engaged with stakeholders to increase company performance enabling expansion of its Home Care living placements enabling the company to increase its capacity for NHS complex care referrals. Implemented a robust system working closely with the Local Council on a project pilot to measure and highlight learning outcomes and the impact of its activities within the community. Developed a company-wide website to improve National & International presence alongside establishing social media network presence.

Pre-registration Pharmacist (July 2018- July 2019) **Dalesway Pharmacy**

- Work towards the 72 standards set out by the GPHC and excel at them numerous times.
- Act in a professional manner while dealing with patients and other healthcare professionals.
- Manage my time between studying and working 40 hours
- Identify common interactions between commonly used drugs and foods and act appropriately to ensure patient safety.
- Supported the pharmacist in all duties including managing staff and ordering of medication.
- Counsel patients on over the counter medication use and recommend medication for minor ailments
- Take in prescriptions, label, dispense and give them out including out of hours referrals.
- Under supervision from my tutor did legal, clinical and accuracy checks on private and NHS prescriptions
- Managed care home prescriptions and dossett trays

Pharmacy Assistant (Nov 2015- Dec 2017) HBS Pharmacy

Meir Health Care Centre,

- Dispensed prescription medication and other medical products to patients under direction of pharmacist
- Use Electronic Prescription Service and dispense and endorse electronic prescriptions
- Counted pills, labelled bottles, sort prices, and compounds medications to prepare prescriptions for patients as directed
- Performed administrative duties, including answering the phone, receiving and inputting prescription orders, operating cash registers, and restocking
- Gathered, organised, and assessed patient information
- Monitors prescription-filling process to ensure compliance with relevant regulations and pharmacy policies
- Maintains electronic patient information using the software's PharmacyManager and PRoScript

Fundraiser and Voluntary worker in Peru (Jun -Aug 2015)

Camps International NGO

- Directly involved fundraising, proposal and report- writing and persuaded Keele University board of directors to donate £1,000 to the organisation.
- Spent a month in Peru building an ICT lab for the local school, this involved hard labour.

Pharmacy Assistant Technical Officer (Oct 2016 - June 2017) University Hospital of North Midlands

- providing a ward stock topping up service of pharmaceutical products,
- reception duties including logging information,
- receiving goods from the suppliers
- dispensing prescriptions
- housekeeping duties.

Youth Mentor (2015-2016)

City of Stoke-on-Trent Council

- Successfully engaged the youths at Excel Academy to create and advertise a project that
 would benefit the community. For example, litter picking and spending time with the
 elderly and helping the homeless.
- Prepared presentations, posters for the class and assisted the youths with marketing and advertising their projects.

Hotel and Bar Assistant (May 2012 – August 2015)

Promoted to Supervisor in 2014

Alton Towers Hotel

- Consistently provided professional, friendly and engaging service.
- Skillfully promoted items on beverage lists and restaurant specials.
- Displayed enthusiasm and knowledge about the restaurant's menu and products.
- Recruited and trained staff to provide the department with appropriate skills and motivated the workforce.
- Efficiently, used the Opera system which is a property management system practiced by leading hotel brands all over the world.

Education:

Master of Pharmacy (MPharm): Keele University 2014 - 2018

- Grade Awarded: 2:1
- Wrote a paper after undertaking a project titled "Age, gender and social patterns in longterm opioid use for chronic non-cancer pain in primary care settings" and was awarded first class.
- Gained comprehensive clinical awareness
- Gained through understanding of best prescription and pharmacy practices
- Excellent interpersonal and management skills

- Proficient user of IT
- Knowledge of the pharmacology and pharmacokinetics of drugs

A Levels: Blythe Bridge Sixth Form 2012 – 2014

- Mathematics A, Chemistry B, Business Studies B
- AS Biology
- Awarded the Best Students in Mathematics and Business Studies

Area of expertise:

- Exceptional patient care and interaction
- Ability to handle , analyse and interpret data efficiently and accurately
- Pharmaceutical distribution familiarity
- Excellent written and oral communication.
- Interpersonal skills.

Hobbies and Interests

I assist with mentoring teenagers and young adults at my local church. I enjoy writing poetry, spoken word, travelling, and playing tennis.

References:

Available on Request